You will be changed.
Wicked: For Good is a fantasy, adventure, romance film directed by Jon M. Chu.
As an angry mob rises against the Wicked Witch, Glinda and
Elphaba will need to come together one final time.
With their singular friendship now the fulcrum of their futures, they will need to truly see each
other, with honesty and empathy, if they are to change themselves, and all of Oz, for good.
Elphaba, played by Cynthia Erivo.
Glinda, played by Ariana Grande.
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Madame Morrible, played by Michelle Yeoh.
Fiyero / The Scarecrow, played by Jonathan Bailey.
Boq / The Tin Man, played by Ethan Slater.
Wicked: For Good (also known as Wicked: Part Two) is a 2025
American musical fantasy film directed by Jon M.
Chu and written by Winnie Holzman and Dana Fox.
The sequel to Wicked (2024), it adapts the second act of the 2003 stage musical by Stephen Schwartz and
Holzman, which was loosely based on Gregory Maguire's 1995 novel, a re-imagining of L.
Frank Baum's 1900 novel The Wonderful Wizard of Oz and its 1939 film adaptation.
Ariana Grande, Cynthia Erivo,  Jonathan Bailey, Ethan Slater, Bowen Yang,
Michelle Yeoh, and Jeff Goldblum return from the first film.
Set in the Land of Oz before and during the events of The Wonderful Wizard of Oz, the film follows Elphaba
and Glinda in their new identities as the Wicked Witch of the West and Glinda the Good.
Universal Pictures and Marc Platt, who both produced the stage
musical, announced the film adaptation in 2012.
After a long development and multiple delays, partly due to the COVID-19
pandemic, Chu was hired to direct, with Erivo and Grande cast in 2021.
The adaptation was split into two parts to avoid omitting
plot points and further develop the characters.
Principal photography on both films began in December 2022 in England, was interrupted in July
2023 by the 2023 SAG-AFTRA strike, and resumed and concluded in January 2024.
Wicked: For Good premiered at the Suhai Music Hall in São Paulo on November 4,
2025, and was released in the United States on November 21.
It has grossed $525 million on a $150 million budget, becoming the
second-highest-grossing Oz film and musical film adaptation.
Both the National Board of Review and the American Film Institute listed it among the top-ten films of 2025, and it received several
accolades, including nominations for five Golden Globe Awards and seven Critics' Choice Awards (including Best Picture).
The film explores themes of witch, based on novel or book,
musical, female friendship, based on play or musical.
The tone is emotional.